# Lorenzo Fabbri | Resume

Status: PhD Student at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health

Field: Causal Inference, Epidemiology

Barcelona, Spain

# Summary

I am a PhD student at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health (ISGlobal). I work under the supervision of Prof. Martine Vrijheid. My main topic of interest is the use of modern Causal Inference methods to answer questions in the broad field of Environmental Neuroepidemiology. I am also profoundly interested in Open Science and Reproducible Research.

I received my Bachelor's degree in Biotechnology and my Master's degree in Quantitative and Computational Biology. You can find me on Twitter, Bluesky, Mastodon, and GitHub.

## Working Experience

#### PhD Student

Barcelona Institute for Global Health (Barcelona, ES)

2021 - Present

\* NA

# Student Research Assistant Fellowship

Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)

2017 - 2017

\* NA

#### Honors and Awards

## Outstanding Abstract by a Student

International Society for Environmental Epidemiology

2022

\*

#### **Publications**

#### Conference Presentations

# Education

## PhD Programme in Biomedicine

Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Barcelona, ES)

2021 - Present

\* NA

# M.Sc. in Quantitative and Computational Biology

Università degli Studi di Trento (Trento, IT)

2017 - 2019

\* NA

#### M.Sc. Student in Computational Science

Università della Svizzera italiana (Lugano, CH)

2016 - 2017

\* NA

#### B.Sc. in Biotechnology

University of Parma (Parma, IT)

2012 - 2016

\* NA

# Continuing Education

Service

Skills